<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="state_part1">
        <item>Visakhapatnam</item>
        <item>Tawang</item>
        <item>Guwahati</item>
        <item>Gaya</item>
        <item>Rock Garden</item>
        <item>Chitrakot Waterfall</item>
        <item>Places to visit</item>
        <item>Calangute Beach</item>
        <item>Gir National Park</item>
        <item>Gurgaon</item>
        <item>Kullu</item>
        <item>Srinagar</item>
        <item>Kochi</item>
        <item>Gwalior</item>
        <item>Lonavala</item>
        <item>Vantawng Waterfalls</item>
        <item>Kohima</item>
        <item>Puri</item>
        <item>Amritsar</item>


    </string-array>
    <string-array name="city_content">
        <item>Visakhapatnam remains a major sea port of the country. It enjoys a tropical climate throughout the year, bringing travellers from all over the world. Its main lures include serene beaches, beautiful hilltops and an exciting wildlife sanctuary. For enjoying a great stay with your family, the Araku Valley here is a great pick.</item>
        <item>Tawang has a stunning geography with Tibet to its north, Bhutan to its south-west and Sela range to its West and Kameng to its east. The place grabs your soul with its unseen natural beauty. Being located 10000 feet above Mean Sea Level, Tawang has the perfect ambience to feel the silence of nature. It is known for housing the world famous Tawang monastery which is over 400-year-old. Sela Pass, a high-altitude mountain pass, is a spectacular location to visit here. You will be greeted by the beautiful Paradise Lake mid-way which adds to the fun quotient. You can also feed your senses with unique sights of Taktsang Gompa, an ancient monastery nestling with thick mountains.</item>
        <item>Located on the banks of Brahmaputra River, Guwahati remains a highly popular city of Assam. It is a popular tourist hub and is dotted with numerous attractions, including Kaziranga National Park, Kamakhya Temple, Umananda Temple, Assam Rajyik State Museum, Navagraha Temple, and much more. Guwahati is selfishly blessed by the Mother Nature with the most pleasurable retreats, making it a true delight for nature devotees.</item>
        <item>Gaya remains the most visited place in Bihar due to its spiritual significance. This hub for Hindu pilgrims is situated on the bank of River Phalgu. One can see numerous Hindu temples and historical sites nestling around the river. Visit the majestic Mahabodhi Temple known for its architectural splendour. The Vishnupad Temple of Gaya is believed to be built on Lord Vishnu\\’s footprints. To explore some unseen historical wonders, Dungeshwari Cave Temples are ideal choice. However, above all it\\’s the Bodhi Tree of Gaya that remains the most visited site here. This is the place where Buddha attained spiritual enlightenment. Thousands of followers of Buddhism visit this place every year to meditate and attain nirvana.</item>
        <item>Also famous with the name of Nek Chand\\’s Rock Garden, this garden houses unique mosaic of art pieces and sculptures. Every exhibit here is made using industrial and home waste, including broken bangles, tube light pieces and toilet fixtures. It was raised in 1957 and today it houses over 5,000 statues within its premises.</item>
        <item>Often termed as Niagara Falls of India, Chitrakot Waterfalls fascinates every visitor with its amazing beauty. It is located 38 km from Jagdalpur and remains the broadest waterfall in India. It is astonishing to see the water gushing down from a height of 96 ft with width above 1000 feet. People flock here for day picnics amidst ample of nature.</item>
        <item>Delhi has a rich history which can be seen in various historical monuments dotted here. Start your holiday to Delhi by visiting the larger than life Red Fort, a masterpiece belonging to the Mughal era. This red sandstone marvel was constructed in 1638 and makes many jaws drop with its magnanimous walls which stand high with pride till date. The evening sound and light show organised here is a must see as it takes you deep into the memory lanes of India. The majestic looking India Gate also catches the attention of all visitors with its grand 42-meter tall structure. This is a war memorial dedicated to 82,000 Indian and British soldiers who scarified their life during the First World War and the Third Anglo-Afghan War. It is amazing to see the names of 13,300 servicemen engraved on its walls. To know some unheard tales from Indian history, a visit to the Humayun/\\’s tomb is a must. It is the tomb of the Mughal Emperor Humayun. Its impressive architecture and massive red sandstone walls tell a lot about Mughal architecture. The tomb is nesting with beautiful looking Mughal Garden which adds to its beauty. No holiday to Delhi can ever end without visiting the magnificent brave tower Qutub Minar which is known for being the tallest individual tower on the planet. Its flawless carvings are worth exploring and bring many architecture aficionados here.

The only mention of Delhi conjures the images of Rashtrapati Bhawan, residence of the President of India. This impressive piece of architecture   has four floors with 340 rooms. The Mughal Gardens surrounding Rashtrapati Bhawan has been made by using both Mughal and English landscaping styles. The Mughal Gardens remain open for public in February–March every year.
Delhi is home to some of the most spectacular religious places belonging to various religions. The Swaminarayan Akshardham Temple is not only a significant religious place but is also known for its unmatched architecture. The temple paints Hinduism and is dedicated to Lord Swaminarayan. Thousands of people all over the world visit here to seek serenity and spirituality. The temple houses an idol of Lord Swaminarayan apart from 20,000 other deities, important personalities belonging to Indian history and sages. The architecture of Lotus Temple is also impressive. This unique temple symbolizes four religions namely Hinduism, Jainism, Buddhism and Islam. Also, visit the largest mosque in India–Jama Masjid of Delhi. The mosque is so big that it can hold up to 25000 devotees at a time. The Gurudwara Bangla Sahib in central Delhi is a significant Sikh holy spot.
Also, to capture some stunning sites of wildlife, a visit to the National Zoological Park of Delhi is a must. Hop on the safari van and spot Tigers, Leopards, Bears, Foxes, Monkeys, Deer, Antelope, etc.
</item>
        <item>One of the most visited beaches of Goa, Calangute Beach is the biggest beach of North Goa. This remains busy with travellers and locals alike and brims with life all day long. This is a great hub to try a plethora of water sports apart from cherishing beautiful views of the sea. The beach is nestling with numerous beach shops where one can shop and have a whale of a time.</item>
        <item>One of the biggest National parks for spotting Asiatic animals, Gir National Park remains the most visited National Parks in India. This dry deciduous forest is home to over 300 avian species, including great horned owl, crested serpent eagle, and much more. Gir National Park is the sole home of the Asiatic lion. People flock here to partake in breathtaking jeep safaris which take you deep into the jungle where you can peep into the world of wild. One can see over 400 plant species here and 2,375 distinct fauna species. Best time to visit the park is between March and May, when the probability of spotting lions rises.</item>
        <item>The hi-tech city of Haryana, Gurgaon is the second largest city of the state. The city finds place in Mahabharata, and today it is known for being a booming corporate hub. One can find the best night clubs in Gurgaon to party till wee hours. Places to explore in Gurgaon include Sultanpur National Park Bird Sanctuary, Leisure Valley Park, Damdama Lake, Farrukh Nagar Fort, etc.</item>
        <item>One of the most frequented tourist places in India, Kullu is ideal to unwind amidst ample of nature. Located on the banks of the Beas River, Kullu is often termed as the \\’Valley of Gods as it brings to you pristine landscapes. It houses numerous attractions to explore, including Basheshwar Mahadev Temple, Great Himalayan National Park, Sultanpur Palace, Parvati Valley, etc.</item>
        <item>The capital city Srinagar is a blissful retreat for the seekers of peace amidst nature. Visit here and you will be showered with traditional Shikara boats, luxurious houseboats, snow-blanketed mountains and gleaming Dal and Nageen Lake. Every traveller visiting Sri Nagar always visits the renowned Hazratbal Shrine and Jama Masjid for seeking blessing of Prophet Mohammad.  Srinagar is also a great option for numerous fun activities like bird watching in Dachigam Wildlife Sanctuary; water skiing in Dal Lake, Nagin Lake and Bod-dal; golfing in Kashmir Golf Course; trekking in Pir Panjal; and boating in Shikara ride on Dal Lake and Nagin Lake.</item>
        <item>At a distance of 190 km from Coimbatore, 204 km from Trivandrum, 426 km from Mangalore and 516 km from Bangalore, Kochi, also known as Cochin is a port city in Ernakulam district of Kerala. Also referred to as \’The Queen of the Arabian Sea\’, Kochi is the financial capital of Kerala. Kochi is one of the prime tourist places to visit in Kerala.</item>
        <item>A vibrant city that is bustling with life in Madhya Pradesh is Gwalior. The city has experienced the rules of several dynasties and has also patronized the artists and musicians to increase the fame of this place through their songs and writings. All major Rajput clans like Tomars, Pratiharas, Kacchwahas have gifted a rich historical culture to the city. It includes grand palaces, artistic monuments and temples present in the city.</item>
        <item>Lonavala is a town and a hill station Municipal Council in Pune district in the Indian State of Maharashtra. It is known for its production of the hard candy chikki and is also a major stop on the railway line connecting Mumbai and Pune.  The hill stations sprawl over an approximate area of 38 square kilometres (15 sq mi). Tourism peaks during the monsoon season. The name Lonavla is derived from the Sanskrit lonavli, which refers to the many caves like Karla Caves, Bhaja Caves and Bedsa that are close to Lonavla. A trip to Lonavla and Khandala can be combined with sight-seeing visits of Karla, Bhaja and Bedsa caves and also the two fortresses, Lohagad and Visapur.</item>
        <item>Mizoram boasts of having the 13th highest waterfall in the country, Vantawng waterfalls. This is one of the major tourist attractions in Mizoram. Watching the waterfalls gushing from a height between the valleys and the dense jungles is a sight to behold. The spectacular view of the Mizoram waterfalls can leave you in trance and give you an unforgettable experience.</item>
        <item>The capital of Nagaland deserves to be on the must-visit list of everyone. Kohima, originally Kewhira, is pure bliss for anyone who loves being amidst untouched nature. It is located at a height of 1500 meters above sea level. It is surrounded by breath-taking mountains and forests. One can also indulge in adventures like trekking, hiking, and camping in this region. This place is home to the Angami tribe.
While you are here, do visit the Commonwealth War Cemetery. It has graves of over 1400 soldiers who died fighting the Japanese invading India from Burma in World War 2. Other major attractions include the Japfu Peak and Naga Heritage Village among others.
</item>

        <item>A sand artist making a beautiful piece of sand art at the Golden Beach of Puri
If you are planning to visit Odisha for a relaxing vacation by the sea, Puri is the place to be. Ranked among the top tourist places in Odisha, Puri is known for its sun-kissed beaches, age-old temples, and local bustling markets that tempt tourists round the year. It is also among the original Char Dhams that hold significance in the Hindu religion.
Key attractions In Puri: Puri Beach, Puri Beach Festival, Puri Jagannath temple, Chilika Lake and Bird Sanctuary, and Gundicha Ghar Temple
</item>
        <item>The city known for legends, patriotism, and spirituality, Amritsar is found listed at the top when anyone talks about the religious places to visit in Punjab. Home to the Golden Temple, or Sri Harmandir Sahib, this is among the most significant pilgrimage site for Sikhs. You will find a lot of Punjab famous monuments. The narrow lanes of Amritsar are arrayed with shops selling colourful juttis, suits and more. A foodie cannot have enough of Amritsari Kulche, Butter Chicken, Lassi – the list is long!</item>



    </string-array>
</resources>

