<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="state_contents">

        <item>Cladding the south-eastern coast of India, Andhra Pradesh is the 4th biggest state of India. The state enjoys a rich history and remains a significant Buddhist centre as well. Many legendary dynasties ruled Andhra Pradesh in the past, including the Pallavas, the Chalukyas, the Kakatiyas and the Mughals. Each of these dynasties infused their own unique cultures into the state which result in its today\’s multicultural image.
It is bounded by the Indian states of Tamil Nadu to the south, Karnataka to the southwest and west, Telangana to the northwest and north, and Odisha to the northeast. The eastern boundary is a 600-mile (970-km) coastline along the Bay of Bengal. Telangana was a region within Andhra Pradesh for almost six decades, but in 2014 it was carved off to form a separate state. The capital of both Andhra Pradesh and Telangana is Hyderabad, in west-central Telangana.
The state draws its name from the Andhra people, who have inhabited the area since antiquity and developed their own language, Telugu. Andhra Pradesh came into existence in its present form in 1956 as a result of the demand of the Andhras for a separate state. Although it is primarily agricultural, the state has some mining activity and a significant amount of industry. Area 106,204 square miles (275,068 square km). Pop. (2011) 84,665,533.
</item>
        <item>There are moments when nature stuns you to the core. You come face to face with places which seem unknown but still have a charm to hold you forever. And one such destination is Arunachal Pradesh - abode of the dawn-lit mountains. Blessed with charming mountains, uncharted passes, serene lakes and renowned monasteries – this Indian state has simplicity to die for. As you step into this wonderland, you are showered with remarkable array of flora and fauna, surrounded by unique glaciers, high rising meadows and sub-tropical forests.

Arunachal Pradesh, meaning “Land of the Rising Sun,” long has been a recognized region of the Indian subcontinent, receiving mention in such ancient Hindu literature as the Kalika-purana and the epic poems Mahabharata and Ramayana. Formerly known as the North East Frontier Agency (from the British colonial era), the area was part of Assam until it was made the Indian union territory of Arunachal Pradesh in 1972, and in 1987 it became an Indian state. The region, however, has been the subject of an ongoing sovereignty dispute between India and China. Area 32,333 square miles (83,743 square km). Pop. (2011) 1,382,611.
</item>
        <item>The spectacular gateway to North-East India, Assam remains the most beautiful state of India. The state has a wealth of nature which is untouched and unexplored. This nature lover\’s paradise pampers you with majestic sights of Brahmaputra River and wonderful hills. Tea plantation of Assam can never be missed. They stretch all over the state and look like a never ending emerald blanket. Locals of Assam lead a simple life and are deeply rooted to their cultures and traditions. An interaction with them gives you a clear insight of their active way of living which is simple yet unique in its own way.
It is located in the northeastern part of the country and is bounded to the north by the kingdom of Bhutan and the state of Arunachal Pradesh, to the east by the states of Nagaland and Manipur, to the south by the states of Mizoram and Tripura, and to the west by Bangladesh and the states of Meghalaya and West Bengal. The name Assam is derived from the word asama, meaning “peerless” in the now extinct Ahom language. The neighbouring states of Arunachal Pradesh, Nagaland, Mizoram, and Meghalaya were once part of Assam. The capital, formerly Shillong (now the capital of Meghalaya), was shifted to Dispur, a suburb of Guwahati, in 1972. Area 30,285 square miles (78,438 square km). Pop. (2011) 31,169,272.
</item>
        <item>The Culturally rich and historically flamboyant, Bihar is a prosperous Indian state. The state has a deep association with Buddhism and Jainism, which lure numerous pilgrims from all over the world. It is home to the holiest Bodhi Tree under which Prince Siddhartha meditated to attain enlightenment. Visit here and experience its wonderful past engraved in the monuments sprinkled here.
It is bounded by Nepal to the north and by the Indian states of West Bengal to the northeast and Uttar Pradesh to the west. In November 2000 the new state of Jharkhand was created from Bihar\’s southern provinces and now forms the state\’s southern and southeastern borders. The capital of Bihar is Patna.

Bihar occupied an important position in the early history of India. For centuries it was the principal seat of imperial powers and the main focus of Indian culture and civilization. The derivation of the name Bihar from the Sanskrit vihara (Buddhist monastery) reflects the prominence of such communities in the region in ancient times. Area 38,301 square miles (99,200 square km). Pop. (2011) 103,804,637
</item>
        <item>Chandigarh is perhaps the happiest city of India brimming with matchless zeal. The locals of the city are known for their lively nature and a special inclination towards food. The city\’s infrastructure is the most planned one in India and thus, never fails to impress visitors.  Chandigarh resides on the foothills of the Shivalik range which gives it an incredible backdrop. Often termed as the Garden city of India, Chandigarh is home to more than its fair share of gardens.

Lying within the territory of Chandigarh are the city of Chandigarh, several towns, and a number of adjoining villages. Administration of the territory\’s government is provided by the governor of Punjab, who is assisted by a senior officer; both are appointed by the national government. Chandigarh city is the capital of the territory and of the states of Haryana and Punjab. Chandigarh\’s name, meaning “stronghold of the goddess Chandi,” is derived from the Chandi Mandir, a temple dedicated to the goddess that is located near the town of Mani Majra. Area union territory, 44 square miles (114 square km). Pop. city, (2001) 808,515; union territory, (2001) 1,063,000; city, (2011) 960,787; union territory, (2011) 1,054,686.
</item>
        <item>The state offers you a perfect fusion of tribes, history, nature and wildlife, leaving you longing for more. Visit Chhattisgarh to experience its immaculate nature, including striking waterfalls, picturesque plateaus and twisting rivers. The state remains a feast for the lens of every photographer seeking a picture perfect landscape.

Chhattisgarh, state of east-central India. It is bounded by the     Indian states of Uttar Pradesh and Jharkhand to the north and      northeast, Odisha (Orissa) to the east, Telangana (formerly part of Andhra Pradesh) to the south, and Maharashtra and Madhya Pradesh to the west. Its capital is Raipur. Area 52,199 square miles (135,194 square km). Pop. (2011) 25,540,196.
</item>
        <item>The National Capital Delhi is rightly called the very heart of India. Bustling streets, vibrant locals, historic grandeur, modern charm, splendid food items, and blissful cultures – Delhi is all this and a lot more. The vividness of this city is such that one needs more than a lifetime to explore it inch by inch. From sky scraping multinational companies redefining the word modern to colonial-era buildings narrating legendary stories of the past, the contrast seen here is unbelievable.

One of the country\’s largest urban agglomerations, Delhi sits astride (but primarily on the west bank of) the Yamuna River, a tributary of the Ganges (Ganga) River, about 100 miles (160 km) south of the Himalayas. The national capital territory embraces Old and New Delhi and the surrounding metropolitan region, as well as adjacent rural areas. To the east the territory is bounded by the state of Uttar Pradesh, and to the north, west, and south it is bounded by the state of Haryana
</item>
        <item>Beautifully tucked into the Western coast of India, Goa is though the smallest Indian state, its larger than life spirit makes its big. With some of the most beautiful beaches weaved together, it is the real beach paradise of India welcoming travellers from all over the world. Nightlife of Goa needs no introduction. The state hosts some of the most pulsating parties after dusk which transform it into a party ground for veteran party goers.

Goa, state of India, comprising a mainland district on the country\’s southwestern coast and an offshore island. It is located about 250 miles (400 km) south of Mumbai (Bombay). One of India\’s smallest states, it is bounded by the states of Maharashtra on the north and Karnataka on the east and south and by the Arabian Sea on the west. The capital is Panaji (Panjim), on the north-central coast of the mainland district. Formerly a Portuguese possession, it became a part of India in 1962 and attained statehood in 1987. Area 1,429 square miles (3,702 square km). Pop. (2011) 1,457,723.
</item>
        <item>Known for its majestic forts and palaces, breathtaking national parks and holiest shrines -Gujarat is the sixth largest state of India. Locals of this culturally rich state are deeply rooted to their traditions and follow their religion by heart. From the most religious Dwarkadhish Temple to the Great Rann of Kutch, from the astonishing Marine National Park to the awe-inspiring Sun Temple, sightseeing attractions in Gujarat are boundless.

Gujarat has a rich history as it was one of the most significant centres of the Indus Valley Civilization. Since then it has grown as an ultra modern state where one can see some of the biggest exemplars of modern times.
The state is bounded primarily by Pakistan to the northwest and by the Indian states of Rajasthan to the north, Madhya Pradesh to the east, and Maharashtra to the southeast. Gujarat also shares a small segment of its southeastern border with the Indian union territory of Dadra and Nagar Haveli, and, together with the Arabian Sea, it surrounds the territory of Daman and Diu. The coastline of Gujarat is 992 miles (1,596 km) long, and no part of the state is more than 100 miles (160 km) from the sea. The capital is Gandhinagar, on the outskirts of the north-central city of Ahmadabad (Ahmedabad)—the former capital, the largest city in the state, and one of the most-important textile centres in India. It was in Ahmadabad that Mohandas (Mahatma) Gandhi built his Sabarmati ashram (Sanskrit: ashrama, “retreat” or “hermitage”) as a headquarters for his campaigns against British rule of India.
</item>
        <item>\’The Abode of God\’, the state of Haryana is ideal to walk through some majestic places dripping in the waters of spirituality. The state has a legendary history which clearly shows in the cities dotted here. It is beautifully set in the foothills of Aravalli, which add to its natural exquisiteness. Today, it stands as an impressive Indian state with ancient temples, imposing architecture and abundance of greenery.

Haryana was constituted on November 1, 1966, as a result of the partition of the former state of Punjab into two separate states—Punjabi-speaking Punjab and Hindi-speaking Haryana. Although the reorganization followed demands made by the Sikh community for a Punjabi suba (Punjabi-speaking province), it also substantially met the aspirations of people in the Hindi-speaking region of Punjab for a Vishal Haryana (Greater Haryana). The name Haryana, from Hari (the Hindu god Vishnu) and ayana (home), means “The Abode of God.” Area 17,070 square miles (44,212 square km). Pop. (2011) 25,353,081.
</item>
        <item>With stunning snowy peaks and rising and falling river valleys, Himachal Pradesh remains the most popular adventure holiday destination in India. This is definitely a place that lets you push your limits and partake in some heart pumping adventure activities, including trekking, climbing, rafting, paragliding and skiing. Travellers visit here to experience the untouched horizons, which are serene and spectacular. Himachal has been home to centuries-old Buddhist cultures, which can be seen in tiny villages sprinkled here.

The city of Shimla was the summer headquarters of preindependence British viceroys; it is now the state capital and, at an elevation of about 7,100 feet (2,200 metres), one of the largest and most popular mountain resorts in the country. Formerly a union territory, Himachal Pradesh became a state of India on January 25, 1971. Area 21,495 square miles (55,673 square km). Pop. (2011) 6,856,509.
H
</item>
        <item>A pure heaven on earth, Jammu and Kashmir, a northern Indian state, is perhaps an ideal destination to delve into the wonders of Mother Nature. The scenic landscapes and snow-capped mountains of this state make every human soul fall in love with it. The state remains highly popular among honeymooners seeking some moments of serenity to start their new bond of love. It houses numerous wonders of nature apart from a rich historic background.

Jammu and Kashmir, formerly one of the largest princely states of India, is bounded to the northeast by the Uygur Autonomous Region of Xinjiang (China), to the east by the Tibet Autonomous Region (China) and the Chinese-administered portions of Kashmir, to the south by the Indian states of Himachal Pradesh and Punjab, to the southwest by Pakistan, and to the northwest by the Pakistani-administered portion of Kashmir. The administrative capitals are Srinagar in summer and Jammu in winter. Area 39,146 square miles (101,387 square km). Pop. (2011) 12,541,302.
</item>
        <item>Kerala is a state on the southwestern Malabar Coast of India. It was formed on 1 November 1956, following the passage of the States Reorganisation Act, by combining Malayalam-speaking regions of the erstwhile states of Travancore-Cochin and Madras. Spread over 38,863 km2 (15,005 sq mi), Kerala is the twenty-third largest Indian state by area. It is bordered by Karnataka to the north and northeast, Tamil Nadu to the east and south, and the Lakshadweep Sea[11] to the west. With 33,387,677 inhabitants as per the 2011 Census, Kerala is the thirteenth-largest Indian state by population. It is divided into 14 districts with the capital being Thiruvananthapuram. Malayalam is the most widely spoken language and is also the official language of the state</item>
        <item> Madhya Pradesh is a state in central India. Its capital is Bhopal, and the largest city is Indore, with Jabalpur, Gwalior, Ujjain being the other major cities. Madhya Pradesh is the second largest Indian state by area and the fifth largest state by population with over 75 million residents. It borders the states of Uttar Pradesh to the northeast, Chhattisgarh to the southeast, Maharashtra to the south, Gujarat to the west, and Rajasthan to the northwest. Before 2000, when Chhattisgarh was a part of Madhya Pradesh, Madhya Pradesh was the largest state in India and the distance between the two furthest points inside the state, Singoli and Konta, was 1500 km.</item>
        <item>Maharashtra is a state in the western peninsular region of India occupying a substantial portion of the Deccan Plateau. It is the second-most populous state and third-largest state by area. Spread over 307,713 km2 (118,809 sq mi), it is bordered by the Arabian Sea to the west, the Indian states of Karnataka and Goa to the south, Telangana to the southeast and Chhattisgarh to the east, Gujarat and Madhya Pradesh to the north, and the Indian union territory of Dadra and Nagar Haveli and Daman and Diu to the north west. It is also the world\’s second-most populous subnational entity.</item>
        <item>Manipur is a state in northeastern India, with the city of Imphal as its capital. It is bounded by the Indian states of Nagaland to the north, Mizoram to the south, and Assam to the west; Myanmar lies to its east. The state covers an area of 22,327 square kilometres (8,621 sq mi) and has a population of almost 3 million, including the Meitei, who are the majority group in the state, the Pangals or the Pangans, Naga tribes, Kuki/Zo tribes and other communities, who speak a variety of Sino-Tibetan languages. Manipur has been at the crossroads of Asian economic and cultural exchange for more than 2,500 years. It has long connected the Indian subcontinent and Central Asia to Southeast Asia, China, Siberia (Russia), Micronesia and Polynesia, enabling migration of people, cultures, and religions.</item>
        <item>Nagaland is a state in northeastern India. It is bordered by the state of Assam to the west, Arunachal Pradesh and Assam to the north, Myanmar to the east, and Manipur to the south. The state capital is Kohima, and the largest city is Dimapur. It has an area of 16,579 square kilometres (6,401 sq mi) with a population of 1,980,602 per the 2011 Census of India, making it one of the smallest states of India. Nagaland is one of three states in India where the population is mostly Christian.</item>
        <item>Odisha also formerly Orissa, is an Indian state located on the eastern coast of India. It neighbors the states of West Bengal and Jharkhand to the north, Chhattisgarh to the west and Andhra Pradesh to the south. Odisha has a coastline of 485 kilometres (301 mi) along the Bay of Bengal. It is the 8th largest state by area, and the 11th largest by population. The state has the third largest population of Scheduled Tribes in India.</item>
        <item>Punjab is a state in northern India. Forming part of the larger Punjab region of the Indian subcontinent, the state is bordered by the Indian union territory of Jammu and Kashmir to the north, and the Indian states of Himachal Pradesh to the east, Haryana to the south and southeast, and Rajasthan to the southwest. It is bordered by the Pakistani province of Punjab to the west. The state covers an area of 50,362 square kilometres, 1.53% of India\’s total geographical area. It is the 20th-largest Indian state by area. With 27,704,236 inhabitants at the 2011 census, Punjab is the 16th-largest state by population, comprising 22 districts. Punjabi is the most widely spoken and official language of the state. The main ethnic group are the Punjabis, with Sikhs (58%) and Hindus (38%). The state capital is Chandigarh, a Union Territory and also the capital of the neighbouring state of Haryana. The five tributary rivers of the Indus River from which the region took its name are Sutlej, Ravi, Beas, Chenab and Jhelum Rivers; Sutlej, Ravi and Beas are part of the Indian Punjab.</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>

